+41 76 279 1887 Geneva, Switzerland adrianalan.pol@gmail.com

Adrian Alan Pol

adrianalan.me GitHub: @AdrianAlan LinkedIn: @AdrianAlanPol Publications

Software engineer and machine learning researcher working on a 500 M\$ physics experiment with 4000 scientists. Cooperating in multi-disciplinary teams to integrate state-of-the-art deep learning in the production code. Research interests include computer vision, anomaly detection, model sparsity and optimization for inference. Published in high-impact factor journals and conferences: ICLR, NeurIPS PS, Nature Machine Intelligence.

EXPERIENCE

Princeton University

Princeton, NJ, United States

Postdoctoral Research Associate (Python, C++)

from February 2022

- Leading a team of 5 on data-driven anomaly detection of rare physics events in the Large Hadron Collider.
- Improved model sensitivity to novelties by 3x for the same false positive baseline rate using deep autoencoders.
- Reduced network inference latency to 80 ns by using knowledge distillation and deploying the model on FPGA.
- Conducted research on novel heuristics for network pruning and heterogeneous quantization, accepted to ICLR.
- Communicated CERN's mission to over 50 groups visiting the CMS experiment as an official CERN guide.

CERN Meyrin, Switzerland

Senior Fellow / Doctoral Student (Python, C++)

October 2016 - January 2022

- Implemented and integrated the first ConvNet in the CMS experiment's production code, currently in use.
- Improved sensitivity to detecting hardware failures from 26% to 98% and reduced detection delay by half.
- Developed particle detection model using YOLO framework and accelerated its inference by $8\times$ with TensorRT.
- Co-authored the Artificial Intelligence for High Energy Physics book with the foremost experts in particle physics.
- Convened group's journal club to exchange ideas and stay updated with machine learning research.

Mendix (Siemens)

Rotterdam, the Netherlands

Software Engineer (JavaScript, Python, Scala, C#)

March 2016 - August 2016

- Enhanced the usability and security of Mendix mobile applications, removing 60% of loading time by optimizing the data fetching process and simplifying the login process by introducing PIN-based access.

CERN Meyrin, Switzerland

Software Engineering Intern (Python, JavaScript)

October 2014 - November 2015

- Saved 6000 yearly person-hours by designing and deploying a web-based interactive visualization monitoring tool.

IBM Amsterdam, the Netherlands

Software Engineering Intern (Java, JavaScript)

June 2014 - September 2014

- Enhanced customer experience by designing and developing a mobile application for content recommendations that used a blend of content-based and collaborative filtering.

TECHNOLOGIES

Python, JavaScript, TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch, ONNX, TensorRT, Scikit, Pandas, React, Flask, Node

EDUCATION

University of Paris-Saclay

PhD in Computer Science; Thesis:

Orsay, France

October 2016 - June 2020

Technical University of Denmark

MSc in Telecommunications Engineering; Thesis: ♂

Kongens Lyngby, Denmark September 2012 - January 2016

Lodz University of Technology

Lodz, Poland
October 2008 - February 2012

BEng in Electrical Engineering